Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Agricultural Economics records, 1892-1988
New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Agricultural Economics records, 1892-1988
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Agricultural Economics records, 1892-1988
21-10-694
New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Agricultural Economics.
22.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, a scrapbook, reports, census schedules, financial records, and other files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and other records concerning the Department of Agricultural Economics.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Mainly administrative correspondence of Carl E. Ladd, Albert R. Mann, William I. Myers, and George F. Warren concerning the Departments of Farm Crops (1907-09), Farm Crops and Farm Management (1909-11), Farm Management (1911-19), and Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (1919-), of which Warren was head, indicating the development of teaching and research in farm management at the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell, and correspondence concerning general problems in agricultural economics; also, some correspondence of Howard Conklin, Chester C. DuMond, and Edward R. Eastman; papers pertaining to the building of Warren Hall (1933), the new agricultural economics building, including requests for equipment from professors, lists of equipment needed and ordered, invoices, specifications and plans, and questions and suggestions from professors; correspondence, transcripts, and photographs (1931-48) relating to applications for admission to graduate studies and for departmental assistantships; files on milk marketing and prices, vegetable information, cooperative organizations' accounting data, financial statements, bylaws, and monthly and annual reports; seven albums (1908-19) containing photographs of New York State farms, farm buildings, equipment, stock, crops, regional conditions, and farmers' practices, with accompanying comments, and a scrapbook (1910-16), containing examination questions and exercises from farm management courses; travel vouchers and requests,1920-1962.
In addition, a report (1 volume mimeograph), concerning action taken (ca.1929) on proposals made in a 1928 survey of the Agricultural Experiment Station and the New York State Colleges of Agriculture and Home Economics by E. W. Allen, Chief of the Office of Experiment Stations in the United States Department of Agriculture, and Harlan P. Updegraff; an correspondence with the Bureau of the Census in Washington, DC, memoranda, expense vouchers, suggestions, enlarged photocopies of sample census schedules, minutes of the Census Advisory Committee, and other papers (1909-1929) pertaining to the preparation, tabulation, and results of censuses taken during those years and to George F. Warren's work on the Census Advisory Committee and as a Special Agent for the Bureau of the Census.
Poster: "Don't Let Your Work Get Out of Hand... Face It!". prepared by the Department of Agricultural Economics, Cornell University under contract with the Federal Extension Service, U.S. Department of Agriculture, n.d.
Agricultural Economics and Farm Management class material from 1921.
The Legacy of Charles H. Dyson DVD produced for the dedication of the School of Applied Economics and Management, October 1, 2010.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture. Department of Agricultural Economics.; Allen, E. W.; Conklin, Howard.; DuMond, Chester C.; Eastman, Edward Roe, 1885-1970.; Ladd, Carl E., 1888-1943.; Mann, Albert Russell, 1880-1947.; Myers, William Irving, 1991-1976.; Updegraff, Harlan P.; Warren, George F. (George Frederick), 1874-1938.; Cornell University--Buildings.; Cornell University--Examinations.; Cornell University--Graduate students.; United States.Bureau of the Census.; United States. Office of Experiment Stations.
Subjects:
Agriculture, Cooperative.; Agriculture--Economic Aspects.; Census.; Farms.; Farm management.; Milk trade.
Places:
New York (State)
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Specifications.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Building plans are restricted to permission of the office of Planning Design and Construction.
CONTAINER LIST
- Dr. Mann, 1928-1932 (Box 1)
- Dr. Mann, 1933-1940 (Box 2)
- Dr. Ladd, 1911-1932 (Box 2)
- Dr. Ladd, 1932-1938 (Box 3)
- U.S. Bureau of Census, 1907-1929 (Box 3)
- Purchasing Department, 1921-1932 (Box 4)
- Inventory of Building Blueprints, Nov. 11, 1943 (Box 4)
- Equipment Lists, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
- Equipment Inventory, 1932 (Box 5)
- Equipment List, 1932 (Box 5)
- Placement Plans and Diagrams, 1933-1937 (Box 5-6)
- Equipment Ordered and Received, 1933 (Box 6)
- Equipment List and Inventory, 1933 (Box 7)
- Misc. files - C-L, 1933-1940 (Box 8)
- Miscellaneous files - I-O, 1933-1940 (Box 9)
- Miscellaneous files - P-S, 1933-1940 (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous files - T-V, 1933-1940 (Box 11)
- Classification of Equipment, 1933 (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous files - A-C, 1932-1936 (Box 12)
- Specifications, 1931 (Box 12)
- Specifications, 1931-1932 (Box 13)
- Requisitions, 1931 (Box 13)
- Purchase Orders, 1932-1934 (Box 14)
- Memos and some plans concerning the Agricultural Economics Building, 1930-1931 (Box 15)
- Specifications - Agricultural Economics Building, 1931 (Box 15)
- Photograph used in extension bulletins, 1939-1947 (Box 15)
- A.R. Mann Papers, 1914-1931 (Box 16)
- A.R. Mann Papers, 1921-1927 (Box 17)
- A.R. Mann Papers, 1908-1931 (Box 18)
- A.R. Mann et al. correspondence, 1908-1930 (Box 19)
- Poster: "Don't Let Your Work Get Out of Hand... Face It!", Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Committees
  - Agricultural Economics Recreation Committee, 1933-1956 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Agricultural Economics Recreation Committee - Annual Reports and Financial Reports, 1951-1965 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Economics Recreation Committee - Sports Reports, 1959-1967 (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Milk
  - Control Boards - Quebec, 1933-1937 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Dairy Products Act - Revised Statutes, 1925, Chapter 63, as replaced by the Act 23 George V. Chapter 24, and amended by the Act 24 George V, Chapter 27, and the Act 25-26 George V, Chapter 29.
    Assembly Bill No. 229 - An Act respecting milk and dairy products.
  - Boston Market, 1938-1950 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Preliminary Report 1949 - Factors Influencing the Seasonal Adjustment of Milk Production on Farms in the Boston Milkshed
  - Buffalo Market, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Capital District Market, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Dealers Contract for the Troy Milk Producers Cooperative, Inc.
  - Vermont Milk Control, 1933-1939 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    State of Vermont v. Arthur N. Auclair
    Supreme Court, Chittenden Country, Special Term at Rutland November 1938.
    Blank Applications for State of Vermont Milk Licence.
  - Connecticut Milk Marketing, 1941-1945 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - New York Metropolitan Milk Marketing Area, 1938-1951 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    1951 Map of Country Plants in the New York Milkshed
    Article by Dr. M. C. Bond, Cornell University
    Organization Problems of Marginal and Border-line Territory in Reference to Metropolitan Milk Sheds
  - Syracuse Milk Market, 1938-1939 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Letters to Dr. M. C. Bond, Cornell University
  - Milk Prices at New York City Stores, 1938-1939 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Milk Prices Paid to Farmers, 1922-1946 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    American Agriculturist Article, September 16, 1939
    The Causes of Milk Strikes - Leland Spencer
    Anti-C.I.O. Advertisement
  - Philadelphia Milk Prices, 1910-1951 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Letter to Dr. F. F. Hill, Cornell University
  - Retail Milk Prices, 1907-1948 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Newspaper clippings from the Herald Tribune and New York Times
  - Miscellaneous Milk Prices, 1892-1954 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Newspaper clipping from The New York Times
    1892 Contract between R. Miller and the Anglo-Swiss Condensed Milk Company
    Leland Spencer, Cornell University
    Statement Concerning Need for Increase of Class I Price, Niagara Frontier Marketing Area
    Leland Spencer and Herbert Kling, Cornell University
    A Review of the Report of Mayor La Guardia's Milk Committee
  - Miscellaneous Spreads, 1922-1941 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Milk Marketing, 1933-1950 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    Letters to and from Leland Spencer, Cornell University
    Newspaper clipping from the Tribune
    Plan for Adapting New England Milk Marketing to War-Time Needs
- Organizations
  - Accord Farmers' Cooperative Inc., 1928-1932 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Adirondack Farmers' Cooperative Exchange, 1929-1933 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Albion Growers' Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Alfred Farmers' Cooperative Association, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - American Farm Economics Association, 1933-1951 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    Information on the Cornell Breakfast 1941
  - Aroostood Potato Cooperative, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Asbury Grange Cooperative Association, 1928 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Avoca Cooperative Association Inc., 1928 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Baldwinsville Farmers' Cooperative, 1921-1931 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Barker Growers Cooperative Association, Inc., 1929 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Bovina Cauliflower Growers Cooperative Association, Inc., 1929 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Bovina Center Cooperative Cry. Company, 1936-1937 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Camden Grange Accounting Information, 1933-1941 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Camden Grange Annual Reports, 1937-1940 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Camden Grange By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation, 19-181932 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Camden Grange Correspondence, 1930-1938 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Camden Grange Monthly Reports, 1931-1939 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Cassadaga Farmers' Cooperative Association, Inc., 1929-1940 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Castile Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Castle Cooperative Inc., 1922-1931 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Central Cooperative of Gardiner, 1926-1938 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Central N.Y. Potato and Vegetable Council, 1939-1944 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Chautauqua and Erie Grape Growers Association Inc., 1931-1937 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Chautauqua Farmers' Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Chester Grange, 1928-1931 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Clintondale Fruit Growers' Cooperative Inc., 1920-1934 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Clyde Fruit Growers' Cooperative Association Inc., 1929-1937 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Conewango Farmers' Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Connecticut Poultry Producers, Inc., 1930-1931 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Consumers' Gas and Oil Company - Watertown, New York, 1930-1934 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Cooperative Consumers Society, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1942-1943 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Cooperative Consumers Society, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1943-1944 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Cooperative Consumers Society, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Cooperative Consumers Society, Inc. - Financial Statements, 1942-1946 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Cooperative Consumers Society, Inc. - Ithaca Packing Plant, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Cooperative Consumers Society, Inc. - Weekly Sales and Margins, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Cornwallville Grange Threshers' Cooperative Association Inc. Balance Sheet, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Crogham Grange Exchange, Cooperative Association Inc. Balance Sheet, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Dairymen's League Check Survey, 1933-1934 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Dairymen's League Miscellaneous, 1921, 1927-1929 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Dairymen's League Operating Statement, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Dairymen's League Plants List, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Dairymen's League Provisional Contract, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Dolgeville Milk Producers Cooperative Association, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Eastern Flower Growers Cooperative Inc., 1935 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Eden Grape Growers' Cooperative Inc., 1928 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Ellington Farm Products Cooperative Association Inc., 1925 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Erie County Growers' and Shippers Association, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Fancher Growers' Cooperative Association Inc., 1928, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Farmers' Roadside Market Association, 1933, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Farmers' Threshing Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Farmers' Union Livestock Commission, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Fort Plain Milk Company Inc., 1929, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Cooperative Association Accounting Information, 1932-1935, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Cooperative Association Annual Reports, 1932, 1940-1944 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Cooperative Association Correspondence, 1934-1943 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Fruit Shippers Cooperative Association of Hudson Inc., 1943, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Fulton Vegetable Growers Association, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - GLF Cooperative Association Balance Sheets, 1929-1930 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - GLF Cooperative Association Owego Community Machine Services Balance Sheets, 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 23A)
  - GLF Cooperative Association Owego Farm Repair Services Balance Sheets, 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 23B)
  - Cooperative Association Community Service Correspondence and Notes, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Dairy Program (Extension) Cards, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - GLF Facts and Figures, 1928-1932 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Farm Products Inc., 1942, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - GLF List of Stores and Managers, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - GLF Marketing Reports, 1932, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - GLF Miscellaneous Articles and Correspondence, 1930-1933 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - GLF Produce Auctions, 1936-1938 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - GLF Service Stores Reports, 1930, 1931 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - GLF Volume Analysis Dairy and Poultry, 1932-1934 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - GLF Volume Summaries, 1943-1946 (Box 21, Folder 33 A)
  - Genesee-Orleans Vegetable Growers Cooperative Association Inc., 1930-1936 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Germantown Cooperative Association Accounting Information, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Germantown Cooperative Association Inc. Correspondence, 1930-1936 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Glen and Mohawk Milk Association Inc., 1928 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Gouverneur Cooperative Association Inc., 1928-1930 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Growers Cooperative Grape Juice Company, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Haxton Canning Company, Inc., 1929 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Holstein-Freisian Association, 1923-1927, 1949-1951 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Hortonville Grange Accounting Information, 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Hortonville Grange Correspondence, 1930-1936 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Hudson River Fruit Exchange Incorporated, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Hudson Valley Cold Storage Cooperative, 1934, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Hudson Valley Grape Growers Cooperative Inc, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Cooperative Association Miscellaneous Balance Sheets, 1927-1929 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - International Association of Ice Cream Manufacturers, 1928, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Ionian Growers Cooperative Association Inc., 1928 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Farmers' Market Cooperative Association Inc., 1934 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Keuka Milk Producers Cooperative (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Kinderhook Annual Reports, 1930, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Kinderhook Constitution and By-Laws, 1943, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Knowlesville Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Land O'Lakes Creameries Inc., 1928 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Correspondents' Association, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Leroy Fruit Growers' Cooperative Association, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Linwood Cooperative Association Inc., 1929, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Little Falls Dairy Cooperative Inc., 1927 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Livingstone Manor Cooperative Exchange Inc., 1928 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Kinderhook Correspondence, 1930-1938 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Kinderhook Monthly Reports, 1932-1935 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Long Island Agricultural Council Work Sheets, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Manheim Dairy Cooperative Inc, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Maple Producers Cooperative Association Inc., 1933-1940 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Marion Vegetable Growers Association Inc., 1933, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Marlboro Cooperative Association Inc., 1935, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Maryland State Dairymen's Association, 1929 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Michigan Milk Producers Association, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Middlesex Cooperative Association Inc., 1929, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Milk Dealers' Association of Metropolitan NY, 1943-1948 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Milwaukee Cooperative Milk Producers, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Organizations- Miscellaneous Documents, 1932-1934 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Monroe County Farmers Roadside Market Cooperative, 1931, 1932, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Montreal Milk Producers' Cooperative Agricultural Association, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Naples Grape Growers Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Long Island Duck Growers' Cooperative Association Inc., 1929 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Lowville Producers' Dairy Cooperative Inc., 1939-1943 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Lyons Falls Farmers Cooperative Association, 1928, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Kinderhook Accounting Information, 1930-1944 (Box 22, Folder 33)
- Vegetables
  - Farm Management, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Muck Crops, 1939, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Planting, Harvesting, and Marketing Dates, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Certification, 1942, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Contracting, 1942-1953 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Lists of Processors, 1941-1947 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Pack and Stocks, 1948-1952 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Surveys, 1942, 1944, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - County Data, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Crop Reporting Service, New York State, 1940-1948 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Fruits and Vegetables, 1939, 1945, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Census Data-County: Vegetables, 1939, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Carlot Shipments of Fruits and Vegetables in New York, 1929-1944 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Vegetables: Costs, 1932, 1939-1944 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Farm Pamphlets, 1933-1950 (Box 22, Folder 47)
- Miscellaneous Railroad Documents, 1928-1935 (Box 22, Folder 44)
- New York State Maps, 1918, 1928, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 46)
- Canning Factory Survey, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Sheep and Lamb Prices, 1929 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Lamb and Sheep Publications, 1931-1941 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Livestock Receipts at Buffalo, 1927-1934 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Livestock, 1930-1952 (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
- Rabbits, 1932 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Prices Documents, 1934-1951 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Wool: Prices, Correspondence, Pamphlets, 1927-1938 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Tobacco, 1947-1957 (Box 23, Folder 14)
- Grain, 1950-1955 (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Markets
  - Market Studies
    - New York State Bureau of Markets, Department of Agriculture and Markets Documents, Annual Report on Markets, 1918-1955 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Upstate New York: Ferguson, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Newburgh Market, 1941, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Margaretville Cauliflower Auction, 1937-1939 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Syracuse-V. Nicholson, 1941 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Produce Marketing Facilities in Utica, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Utica- RG Wilcox, Market Planning Prints, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Market Documents, 1935-1954 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Roadside Markets
    - Roadside Markets: Other States, 1926-1932 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, Maps, 1932-1934 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Public Markets
    - Auburn, 1933 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Albany, 1933, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Buffalo, 1931-1941 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Ithaca, 1934, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Ogdensburg, 1923-1932 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Oneonta, 1934 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Utica, 1944, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1929-1935 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Regional Markets
    - Lower Hudson, 1932-1943 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Rochester, 1939, 1950-1957 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Central New York, 1934-1948 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Genesee Valley, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1940 (Box 23, Folder 39)
- Public Problems in Agriculture, 1936-1950 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- New York Agricultural Policy, 1943, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Suggestions for Annual Report, 1932 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- VB Hart- Extension Work, Dean's Report, Miscellaneous, 1927-1930 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Agricultural Adjustment Administration, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- New Jersey Agriculture, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Policy Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1940 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Rutgers University Institute of Rural Economics, 1934 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Master Farmers Pamphlets, 1934-1936 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Land Use Planning Project, 1933-1935 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Land Use Planning Project, 1936-1938 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Land Use Planning Project, 1939-1944 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Land Use Planning Project, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Cornell Graduate School, 1936-1956 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Vegetable Commodity Committee, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Extension- including talks by Earl Butz and John Davis, 1938, 1949-1959, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Census Data County-Worksheets for Graphs, 1979-1934 (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Census Data County- General Factors, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 18)
- Farm Management Costs and Real Estate, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 19)
- Northeast Policy Conference, 1948-1952 (Box 24, Folder 20)
- Agricultural Policy-Extension Conference Northeast, 1948-1952 (Box 24, Folder 21)
- Public Policy, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 22)
- Milk, 1931-1944 (Box 24, Folder 23)
- Agricultural Affairs, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 24)
- Talks: Secretary of Agriculture, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 25)
- Talks: Miscellaneous, 1949-1957 (Box 24, Folder 26)
- Milk, 1928-1942 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Milk Situation, 1928-1942, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Milk Stabilization Committee, 1929, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Milk Utilization, 1932, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Milk Weights and Tests, 1944, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Documents, 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Ithaca "Yellow Sheet", 1932-1933 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- "The Farm Income Situation", 1945-1953 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Farm Cost Accounts, 1927-1939 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- GLF Store Advisory Committee, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Foreign Trade, 1941-1953 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Labor and Wages, 1950-1954 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Electricity Miscellaneous and Extension, 1950-1957 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Cooperatives Cold Storage, 1932, 1950-1955 (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Credit Pamphlets, 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 15)
- Dairy Commodity Comnmittee, 1939-1957 (Box 25, Folder 16)
- New York City Marketing Tours, 1928-1939 (Box 25, Folder 17)
- New York City Marketing Tours, 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Tours: Miscellaneous, 1928-1936 (Box 25, Folder 19)
- 4-H Club, 1946-1956 (Box 25, Folder 20)
- Chester C. DuMond and Edward R. Eastman - Correspondence (Box 26)
- William I. Myers and George F. Warren - Correspondence (Box 27)
- Travel Expense Reports
  - 1920-1928 (Box 28)
  - 1928-1934 (Box 29)
  - 1934-1940 (Box 30)
  - 1941-1945 (Box 31)
  - 1945-1950 (Box 32)
  - 1950-1962 (Box 33)
- History - Agricultural Economics - Cornell, 1932-1952 (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Department Memos, 1961-1976 (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Local Government - New York, 1939-1976 (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Institute for Public Welfare Training, 1959, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 4)
- Institute of Community Leadership, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 5)